[music]
>> Hi everybody. I'm Abby. Nice to meet
you.
From the General Intelligence Company of
New York, which is a big mouthful of a
name. We can also just go by GIC or
General Intelligence. Uh, I'll be
talking today about Frontier Agent
Orchestration. Uh, so before that, just
a little bit about me.
Uh, background, went to Cal, go Bears.
Can't resist an opportunity for a little
go Bears.
Uh, after graduating, I worked at this
company Samsara for a few years. Uh, did
product engineering, built out their
data science team, as well as some
large-scale amount projects. After that,
spent a couple years at an LLM eval
startup and led engineering there for
the last year. Uh, then after leaving
Gantry, so I spent time at Techstars
Commons, which is an accelerator here in
New York.
Here and in New York, uh, where I met my
co-founder Andrew and we started GIC.
Uh, so just a little bit of background
on myself. And that's me in Banff,
Canada, which is very nice place.
Cool. So a little bit about the General
Intelligence Company of New York. I'll
be using the full name every time.
Uh,
so our mission is to enable one person
to run an entire scale business
autonomously.
So let's talk a little bit about how we
plan to do that.
So here's some of our core beliefs.
One is that
a single entrepreneur can operate a
company driven entirely by agents.
And that anyone with an idea and capital
should be able to start and scale a
business. And then the future and now,
the number [clears throat] of
entrepreneurs will increase
dramatically.
So with that, we want to build a system
to help these entrepreneurs run their
business.
So in our system, we will have vertical
agents that accomplish low-level tasks.
And those vertical agents will be
coordinated and managed by horizontal
agents. So you can imagine a business
where you have engineering agents for
building out the features, support
agents for handling customer support,
maybe finance agents for ops, and
marketing agents for running marketing,
all coordinated at the top level by
coordinator agent.
So out of that
whole vision, what we're building is
this, the orchestrator and interface for
the entire business.
So we want to build a system that
basically lets users easily take in
their support tickets and convert them
to automated bug fixes. Track marketing
and build out features. Maybe even look
at subscriptions on the ramp card and
see what's actually being used in the
code base and cancel things that are not
being used.
So to do that, we have this idea called
super optimization, where you have
agents managing agents.
So you have manager agents with
high-level goals.
And they will use low-level agents that
are specifically task-scoped uh, to
accomplish tasks. So you can already
kind of see this happening in the some
of the frontier like coding agent
orchestration systems, where you might
give it a high-level goal like build out
my hot system, and it'll spin off
low-level coding agents to build out
certain components of that.
So to do that and to get all of that
working, you really need to get
multi-agent coordination working, which
is a nice little image here of robots
building something, a well I think. Um,
and this is surprisingly or really not
so surprisingly difficult to do.
And usually when you see multi-agent
coordination kind of in demos or
tutorials or things like that, it looks
something like you have agent, you ask
it to do a task, it kicks off a planner
agent, a research agent, writer agent.
They go and run and you they go and they
run, you get a summary back and you kind
of hope that nothing went wrong in
between.
Uh, in production, a lot of things
always go wrong in between all the time.
And so this talk is a little bit on how
to deal with that and building
multi-agent systems that are resilient
to things going wrong.
And so for that, we have an internal
framework that we call sunflower. And
really this framework is kind of just
our principles for building multi-agent
systems.
And there's [clears throat] really three
core things we believe.
One is that agents should control the
full life cycle of their sub-agents.
Two, that agent delegation should be
async, not synchronous.
And three, that agents should have full
visibility into the system themselves.
So I'll talk about each of these items
today.
First, just starting with controlling
the full life cycle.
So what I mean by that is that agents
should be able to stop their sub-agents.
Uh, they should be able to answer
clarification questions from their
sub-agents. So the point on that is that
sub-agents should be able to ask the
parent agent clarification questions.
They should be able to send messages to
steer their sub-agents.
And they should even be able to restart
their sub-agents with added context.
So if you kind of look at sort of demo
life cycle of agent sub-agent, you have
the user, it sends a request,
we fire off a sub-agent,
>> [snorts]
>> gathers context, info comes back, and
you get a report.
However,
usually agent sub-agent life cycles end
up being a lot more complex.
The user might send a request, you might
fire off the sub-agent, then the user
says, "Oh no, I forgot to add XYZ
context."
You need a way to stop that sub-agent,
gather the added context, and restart
with new context, and run the sub-agent.
And this is just one example of the
added complexity that comes with running
these multi-agent systems.
You can imagine that there's a lot more
complicated scenarios that happens uh,
when you introduce users to your system.
The next item I want to talk about
is async agent delegation.
So one of the core things here is that
we think agent delegation should be
async. Right now in a lot of systems,
sub-agent delegation happens
synchronously.
So if you use something like cursor, you
kind of see when they fire off
sub-agents, it's happening synchronously
and the main agent is just waiting for
the sub-agents to finish up their task,
and then it will collect gather the
information and report back.
We think it should be done a little bit
differently.
When you fire off a sub-agent, the main
agent should be able to do work in
parallel while it's waiting for that
sub-agent.
It should be able to await another
sub-agent, and I'm really
combining a lot of terminology there,
but by waiting I just mean
the parent agent should say that it
wants to be notified when the sub-agent
is done. And whenever the sub-agent is
done, it should be event-driven and
notified asynchronously
when the sub-agent is finished working.
And to be able to get both of those
things actually working in production
systems, you really, really should set
timeouts to avoid being stuck and forget
about a sub and make sure the system
doesn't forget about a sub-agent that's
running.
A lot of things can go wrong. There's a
number of reasons that sub-agents might
not report the results back to parent
agent. So if you're doing async agent
delegation, timeouts are pretty crucial
in making sure that you get the report
back or if the sub-agent went wrong and
some access some external flaky service
or it died for whatever reason, your
system remembers to check back in on the
sub-agent and see what went wrong.
And to be able to see what went wrong,
your system really should have full
visibility into itself.
And this isn't my core point I think for
today. So if you really have one
takeaway for agent implementation,
it's that [snorts] you should build a
system that can observe itself.
Uh, so there's a few ways to do this.
One, you should give it tools to query
its own observability. So we use
Logfire.
Um, so a little plug there. Uh, but you
should give it tools to be able to query
Logfire.
Um, it can be very helpful to do that.
It can query its own trace. It can query
a bunch of child traces in aggregate.
And just giving that tool, you get to
see some interesting behaviors emerge.
For example,
if your system exists is experiencing
some consistent systematic error, say
some external service is down,
and your parent agent starts noticing
that every single sub-agent it's firing
is having some error, it can query
Logfire with SQL and see that, "Oh,
there's some aggregate issue going on.
Maybe I can steer my sub-agents in a
different direction."
Another thing you can do is make all
your child session traces available in a
sandbox,
uh, if your file system pilled, or you
should make them available in some sort
of searchable format.
Uh, this leads to a couple of really
interesting emergent behaviors.
So one is that, again, you get this
aggregate overview of sort of what's
going on in your system. You can grep
and search and see what all your child
session what all your child agents are
of it are up to.
And two, it actually lets you build a
memory system in a pretty lightweight
way. If you have all your child session
traces available to you, you can kind of
have the parent agent remember what it
was working on in the past with the
sub-agent and query and grep and see
what all the child agents have been
working on.
And finally, the third thing we believe
is let it query your own database. Uh,
put limits and guardrails on that. Maybe
you don't let it do delete actions, but
give it some tools that it can actually
query the database and see what's going
on. So
this comes particularly handy if you're
building a system where your sub-agents
are triggered off a cron or some
external event.
Um, this is like
happening in a lot of different agent
features. Cursor has automations, Block
Co-work has
um, cron jobs and things like that. But
if you're building a system like that,
I can pretty much guarantee that your
users are going to wonder why an agent
ran.
And the first thing they're going to do
is not go look at whatever
pretty set up UI you have, which we had,
but they're going to go to your agent
and they're going to ask in all caps why
did you run? And your agent should be
able to answer why it ran. It should be
able to query its trigger logs, should
be able to query its cron schedules, and
it should say this is why it ran.
Um it should be able to maybe edit that
schedule or update the user or tell it
uh all that information.
And so on the right we just have a
little screenshot here of our own system
where it's able to check why a task
died,
check the session in Logfire, and then
update a new
uh an update and start a new session.
If you kind of combine all these things
together, you have the primitives I
think to build a pretty resilient
long-running multi-agent system.
So you still have to build obviously
your own app on top of this, but
using these primitives have helped us
build a system which can really run
autonomously for long periods of time.
Uh if a sub-agent dies for whatever
reason,
uh the timeouts help and the parent
agent can look and see why sub-agent is
dying and restart it.
Uh if the system's experiencing some
issue, it can query itself and see
what's going wrong.
Uh it can adjust trajectory on the fly.
Maybe you have a sub-agent that finished
something and that affects the work of
another sub-agent. It can stop that
sub-agent if it's no longer relevant or
send a message to update that sub-agent.
And it can even learn from its
sub-agents
and maintain some sort of memory of what
you're trying to do long-term with the
system.
So that's all the principles there.
I'm going to transition to a live demo
and we'll see how that goes.
Um
so I will put some caveats that
this is a product that is in alpha.
So [snorts] if it works, then it's cuz I
did such a good job as a CTO.
And if it doesn't work, I'm going to go
yell at my engineers.
So
let's all hope that it works.
Um cool. So this is the product,
co-founder CTO, and
this is uh that's a little small.
Okay.
Cool. So this is one part of the system
we're launching. So we'll be launching
the full system at the end of April.
Um if you used our previous product
co-founder one, this is a little bit
different. This is co-founder two.
Uh so the first part we built out is the
engineering department agent agentic
engineering department. Uh the reason we
went with that is that uh
LLMs are most mature when dealing with
code. And also building this system out
lets us build out our own product
faster. So I'll be showing you
what we're calling CTO.
And so at the top you have the CTO
agent.
And this is the chat here with it.
Uh you also have some charts
that pull data from Logfire,
which isn't super relevant to anything,
but they look really nice and this is a
Logfire conference anyways. Uh so you
get to see all our charts here.
Uh and then on the bottom you can see
the parent agent and how it spins up all
its sub-agents to accomplish different
tasks.
And so this main agent here focuses on
higher-level goals.
And you have the task agent which
actually accomplishes the low-level
goals. If I dive into one
here,
if I click that,
we can see a low-level goal
where it was improve the performance of
the billing page. And this itself is
actually just a another manager agent
whose goal is to improve the billing
performance and can actually spin up
coding agents that go and work on that
task
and spin up browser agents to go
actually
test the feature itself here.
Um and here you can watch it go test the
feature.
And then
finally can report back to the user and
put up a PR for me to look at with
everything said and done. And so that's
an engineer working on a task in our
engineering department.
And at the top level you have the CTO
here. So
I set up some messages beforehand uh to
kind of just
go over what the timeout system looks
like in our own setup. So
here we can see that
we have a little message here, model
sandbox research timed out. So I'll ask
it why
did that time out?
So while it's answering, let me just
scroll up and show the conversation that
we had.
Okay.
So I asked it
how could we add comments to our PR diff
viewer?
And it said, "Okay, let me kick off that
task and see how we could do that."
And then
I was like, "I totally forgot something.
Let me go see how we could kick off a
task agent for each comment that's
added." So it's able to send a message
to that agent and update the progress
while it's going on.
So if we go into that task agent,
let's see if I can find it.
Here we go.
And if we scroll up,
as these LLMs love to do things,
cool. So you can see it starts up the
task
and kicks up a coding agent to look at
that. And then my additional message
comes in to steer this low-level agent
on the right direction. And I'm only
just interacting with this high-level
agent here.
And so
it fired that off and it also set an
await for earlier, which got resumed
here.
And then finally as it was running, I
also said, "Okay,
let's look up how we do timeouts in the
codebase." So this is an example where
we can do parallel work
while the agent the whole system is
working on something else.
So it's like, "Okay, let me look up
this stuff." And right here you can see
where the awaits fire off. And this is a
great example here cuz we have two
things. We have one
where the GitHub PR task actually
finished and the agent was able to
resume uh async and tell me, "Okay,
here's what happened with that task." I
can just interact with this main agent.
Something went wrong with the modal
sandbox search there. And actually that
await just timed out. And rather than
the system forgetting about it, it was
able to see, "Hey, I was waiting on this
thing. What happened?"
And then let me know that
this other research died and it should
go take a look here.
Um I would have liked it to look at its
traces here. It did not do that. So
these things are not always
controllable.
Um but I will ask it to look at its own
traces right now.
Tell me what's up.
All right. And so
in theory it should be able to go and
query Logfire
and hopefully do that a little bit
quicker. But it'll be able to query
Logfire and see its own traces and
see what is going on.
All right.
We love it when live demos go super
well. Okay.
There we go.
And so that right there is a tool for it
to query Logfire and get its full
session history.
And now it's examining and let's see
everything. You get to steal a look and
peek inside our system of all the spans
we log.
Cool. Everything is going great for it
right now. And that is from Logfire.
Awesome. So that is the demo.
Uh and uh finally
if you're interested in starting a
business or you hate your co-founder,
whatever you want to do,
um [snorts]
there's a little QR code here to to sign
up for the waitlist. Awesome. Thank you.
>> [applause]
>> We have a couple minutes for questions.
Who's got a question?
Yeah, I'm I'm curious for your
perspective on like layers of middle
management in like orchestrating focused
and general agents in this sort of
world.
Yeah, one of the
longer-term things we believe is
actually that
a lot of like
scaled multi-agent orchestration is not
going to look actually too dissimilar
from how human organizations are run. I
think obviously there's
some stuff that
we came up with, but a lot of it is like
actually I think we discovered some
pretty good organizational practices
over trial and error of getting
companies to run efficiently. And so
this kind of middle management layer is
actually really big to know our system
and is a core ethos of our system and
it's not just us. I think you can kind
of see this pop up in other like
sort of frontier agent researchers
seeing. For example, I think Cursor had
that blog post on how they built the
browser where they ran a bunch of
million agents and they actually came to
the same conclusion where they found
that system worked better when they
introduced this middle management layer
to sort of coordinate all their like
coding agents. So
middle managers are not dead, they might
just become agents.
>> [laughter]
>> Awesome. Awesome.
Thanks.
I'm curious to learn how you're handling
all of the inner agent communication.
Like what are you doing to broker all
that communication back and forth?
Yeah, so we actually in our system don't
really allow inter-agent communication.
So
it really mostly works if they have
something to report, it goes all the way
up management layers. And so it goes the
coding agent if I have something to
report will go up to that task agent
that's managing it. If the task agent
has something to report that actually
goes up to the CTO agent. As we build
out as we build out the other
departments, we might build out like an
even top-level maybe CEO agent that you
talk to.
Uh we
tried having like agents try to talk to
each other, but it eventually becomes
really chaotic and you as a user
kind of have a hard time grokking all
the inter-agent communication that's
going on.
Uh if we do build out something that
is inter-agent, it would be more of an
observability way where agents can see
what's going on in the system,
uh but they wouldn't be able to talk to
each other. So,
in a way it's our own little cubicle for
each agent.
One more question.
Um I'm curious how your what your CTO's
like system prompt is in terms of what
their overarching
let's say OKR is uh that they're
optimizing for.
Yeah, so for the system prompt for the
CTO is actually
pretty lightweight. We We just tell it
that it's running an engineering team
and it has access to all these like
engineering agents to spin off features,
and really what it should be focused on
is
managing these engineering agents
effectively,
breaking down tasks into
uh subcomponents and dependencies,
and um
basically organizing those effectively.
I just took a little bit of what I do
every day and
put it into the system prompt.
Awesome. Grow shareholder value, make no
mistakes. Exactly. And we said make a $1
million company, make no mistakes. So,
Awesome. Thank you so much, Abby.
Awesome. Thank you.
>> [applause]
[music]